A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Nelson A. Rockefeller family, Series 1008 FA454
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Nelson A. Rockefeller family, Series 1008
1924-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
FA454
16.2 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
Approximately 1,770 prints
Related Archival Materials note
Additional images of Nelson A. Rockefeller and or his interests will be found in the following:
Rockefeller Family Photographs. Most of the photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller in his childhood and many photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller as an adult with his parents can be found in 1005 John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family - Children's Albums or Group Portraits. See also John D. Rockefeller Jr. - Business - 17 West 54th Street.
International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) Archives.
Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C (FA340). This series documents the management of Nelson A. Rockefeller's art collection and includes photos of a portion of the works of art he owned.
Other Finding Aids
For other Nelson A. Rockefeller photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA455 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Room 5600, Rockefeller family office, Series 2
FA456 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial Press Office, Series 3
FA457 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial Press Office, Series 4
FA458 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial, Robert A. (Bob) Wands, Series 5
FA459 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Vice Presidential, Series 6
FA460 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Unprocessed photographs, Series 7
Arrangement note
The Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs are arranged in the following series:
Series 1008: Nelson A. Rockefeller family. Series 2: Room 5600, Rockefeller family office. Series 3: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 4: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 5: Gubernatorial, Robert A. (Bob) Wands. Series 6: Vice Presidential. Series 7: Unprocessed photographs.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series:
Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Other Finding Aids note
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA446 William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA449 John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA451 John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
FA452 Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
For related materials, please see the following finding aids:
FA340 Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C
FA084 International Basic Economy Corporation records
Scope and Contents
The Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008 consists primarily of individual and group family portraits and informals as well as prints of the Rockefeller family homes, Nelson A. Rockefeller's travel, his art interests and philanthropic activities. In addition to documenting a variety of events and activities during Nelson Rockefeller's service as Governor of New York, and as Vice President of the United States, this series also highlights his early government service including the United States Department of State and his efforts as Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.
Rockefeller family -- Art collections; State governments -- United States; Arts; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Art, Modern; New York (State); Political campaigns -- United States; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; New York (N.Y.); Photographs
- Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, 1924-1980; 1008; Approximately 1,770 prints
  Arrangement
  For ease of access the material is further arranged in the following subseries by format and subject:
  Prints (Boxes P 145, P 146, P 147, etc.). Albums (Boxes A 1, A 2, A 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, etc.). 1008A Rodman Clark Rockefeller family. 1008D Michael Clark Rockefeller.
  - Prints, 3.8 Cubic Feet; 350 prints
    - Art Collections (Picasso Tapestries), 1962-1975; 12 prints (Box P 145)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1 print (Box P 145)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1938-1965; 15 prints (Box P 145)
    - Group Portraits - Family and Friends, 1924-1955; 5 prints (Box P 145)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes Richard M. Nixon and Dwight D. Eisenhower.
    - Group Portraits - Friends, 1964; 1 print (Box P 145)
    - Homes, 1 print (Box P 146)
      Monte Sacro
    - Homes - 812 Fifth Avenue, 7 prints (Box P 146)
    - Homes - Vice Presidential Mansion, Naval Observatory, Washington, DC, 1974-1977; 11 prints (Box P 146)
      Photographer: Architectural Digest
    - Margaretta Fitler Murphy (Happy) Rockefeller, 3 prints (Box P 146)
    - NAR - Business - Associates, 2 prints (Box P 146)
    - NAR - Business - International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1947-1968; 32 prints (Box P 147)
    - NAR - Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA), 1942-1946; 23 prints (Box P 148)
    - NAR - CIAA - Inter-American Trade Scholarship, 35 prints (Box P 149)
    - NAR - CIAA - Inter-American Trade Scholarship, 36 prints (Box P 150)
    - NAR - Dignitaries, 1945; 1 print (Box P 151)
      Juan Antonio Rios, President of Chile
    - NAR - U.S. Department of State, 1945; 2 prints (Box P 151)
      United Nations meeting, San Francisco, CA
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years, 1971-1972; 12 prints (Box P 151)
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years - Howard Crawley Memorial Lecture, 1969; 13 prints (Box P 151)
    - NAR - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW), 1 print (Box P 151)
    - NAR - IADC, 1944 May; 19 prints (Box P 152)
      Caricatures
    - NAR - IDAB, 1951; 7 prints (Box P 152)
    - NAR - Miscellaneous, 1937-1949; 2 prints (Box P 152)
    - NAR - Offices, 1979-1980; 25 prints (Box P 152)
    - NAR - Philanthropies - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA), 1965; 1 print (Box P 153)
      Robert Motherwell
    - NAR - Philanthropies - Sleepy Hollow Restorations, 1950s; 2 prints (Box P 153)
    - NAR - Portraits, 1935-1970s; 19 prints (Box P 153)
    - NAR - Travel - American West, 1924; 28 prints (Box P 153)
      Scope and Contents note
      Images taken by Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    - NAR - Travel - Latin America, 1956; 6 prints (Box P 153)
    - NAR - Travel - Yosemite National Park, 1951; 9 prints (Box P 154)
    - NAR - Vice Presidential Years, 1975-1977; 16 prints (Box P 154)
  - Albums, 10 Cubic Feet; Approximately 1,200 prints
    - Mexican Folk Art, 28 prints (Box A 1)
      Photographer - Charles Uht
    - Michael Clark Rockefeller Collection of Primitive Art, 17 prints (Box A 1)
    - Michael Clark Rockefeller - Asmat - Peabody Museum, 41 prints (Box A 4)
    - Michael Clark Rockefeller - Asmat (Baliem Valley), 106 prints (Box A 10)
    - Michael Clark Rockefeller - "Art of the Asmat" Exhibition, 2 copies.; 13 prints and duplicates (Box A 12)
      Photos by Ezra Stoller Associates.
    - Homes - "The Lodge and the Guest House", 1962; 21 prints (Box A 5)
    - Homes - "The Anchorage", 1962 (Box A 13)
    - NAR - Art - Picasso Tapestries, 1955-1970; 11 prints (Box A 16)
    - NAR - Business - IBEC, 1957; 8 prints (Box A 16)
    - NAR - Cartoons, 4 prints (Box A 18)
    - NAR - "Commission on Critical Choices for Americans", 1975 February 28; 36 prints (Box A 8)
      St. Moritz Hotel, New York City
    - NAR - Family, Approximately 50 prints (Box A 15)
      NAR portraits, informals and candids. MFR portraits and informals.
    - NAR - Family - Group Portraits, 1 print (Box A 18)
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years - "The High Rock Nature Conservation Center", Staten Island, NY, 1965; 11 prints (Box A 2)
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years - "Christmas 1972", 14 prints (Box A 6)
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years - "To Governor Nelson Rockefeller from the City Council of Bethlehem", 1972 August 13; 25 prints (Box A 7)
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years - "In Rochester", 1961 September 13-15; 90 prints (Box A 11)
      Scrapbook with associated news clippings
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years - "New York State Dinner - Apollo 8 Astronauts", 1969 January 10; 12 prints (Box A 14)
      Scrapbook with associated correspondence
    - NAR - Gubernatorial Years, 1959-1972; 22 prints (Box A 17)
    - NAR - Informals, 3 prints (Box A 18)
    - NAR - Philanthropies, 1 print (Box A 18)
    - NAR - Philanthropies - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 73 prints (Box A 1)
    - NAR - Philanthropies - "The Peregrine Fund", 1980; 21 prints (Box A 3)
    - NAR - Portraits, 5 prints (Box A 18)
    - NAR - Travel - Europe and the American West, 500 prints (Box A 9)
    - NAR - Travel - Iran, 1957; 2 prints (Box A 18)
    - NAR - Travel - Yosemite National Park, 2 prints (Box A 18)
  - Oversized, 2 Cubic Feet; 87 prints
    - Margaretta Fitler Murphy (Happy) Rockefeller - Portraits, 3 prints (Box O 3)
    - Group Portraits - Family, Approximately 6 prints (Box O 3, Box O 2)
    - Homes - 812 Fifth Avenue, 5 prints (Box O 1)
    - Homes - 812 Fifth Avenue (Box O 1)
      Clippings
    - Homes - Kykuit - Aerials, 1963 March 4; 8 prints (Box O 1)
    - Homes - 13 West 54th Street (Box O 1)
    - NAR - Art - Picasso Tapestries, 7 prints (Box O 2)
    - NAR - Iran - U.S. Visit of Iranian Officials, 1967; 29 prints (Box O 1)
    - NAR - Miscellaneous, 9 prints (Box O 1)
      Compliments of New York Herald Tribune.
    - NAR - Miscellaneous, 3 prints (Box O 1)
    - NAR - Miscellaneous, 3 prints (Box O 4)
    - NAR - Portraits, 9 prints (Box O 2)
    - NAR - Portraits, 4 prints (Box O 3)
    - NAR - Framed Portrait (Box O 5)
      Including: NAR sketch by Thomas Delevett, given to NAR by Henry Kissinger at the 1979 Republican Senate-House Dinnerr.
  - Lantern Slides, 1929; 0.4 Cubic Feet; 128 lantern slides
    - Grenfell Expedition, 1929; 128 lantern slides (Box L 49, Box L 50)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Due to the brittle condition of this material special arrangements are required in order to view materials. Individual items are available at the discretion of RAC.
  - Rodman Clark Rockefeller family, 1968; 1008A; 1 print
    - Prints
      - Rodman Clark Rockefeller family, 1968; 1 print (Box P 154)
  - Michael Clark Rockefeller, 1008D; 1 print
    - Prints
      - Michael Clark Rockefeller, 1 print (Box P 154)